# **GUILHERME FRÓES SILVA**

#### **PhD Researcher**

Prisbane, Australia

in linkedin.com/in/codefroes

orcid.org/0000-0003-4717-2742

## CONTACT INFORMATION

Address: Unit 508, 301 Ann Street. Brisbane City, QLD 4000.

Mobile: +61 433 870 354 Email: g.froessilva@qut.edu.au

# **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS**

Doctor of Philosophy in Electrical Engineering

## **Queensland University of Technology**

Feb 2019 - Ongoing

Prisbane, Australia

School of Electrical Engineering and Robotics

# Master of Philosophy in Electrical Engineering **PUCRS**

## Aug 2015 - Aug 2017

Porto Alegre, Brazil

Thesis "Real-Time Shadow Detection and Removal in Aerial Motion Imagery Application" submitted Aug 2017. GPA: 8.68/10

# BEng in Automation and Control Engineering **PUCRS**

**2009 - 2015** 

Porto Alegre, Brazil

Final year project "Project and Control of a Rotary Dual-Stage Actuator" inspired by the Dual-Stage Actuators of recent HDDs. GPA: 8.2/10

# **ACADEMIC EXCHANGE**

# Sandwich Program in Electrical Engineering The University of Birmingham

m sep 2012 - sep 2013

**♀** Birmingham, UK

One year program including taking several courses and 3 months placement at the Birmingham Centre for Railway Research and Education as an intern.

## **SKILLS**



## **LANGUAGES**

Portuguese English Spanish Native TOEFL score: 104/120 Elementary

## **SUMMARY**

Currently a PhD Student in Queensland University of Technology. Holds a Master of Science Degree in Electrical Engineering from PUCRS - Brazil. Current research involves nonlinear control of interconnected systems. Knowledge in Image/Signal Processing and Control Engineering. Has strong multicultural competence.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### **QUTPRA**



Was awarded with the QUT Postgraduate Research Award (2019)

#### **Student's Representative**



Member of the PUCRS Graduate Program in Electrical Engineering Committee (2016-2017)

#### **United States Air Force Grant**



Participated in the group researching the shadow problem. Funded by Air Force Office of Scientific Research, under project number: FA9550-15-1-0141 (2015-2017)

### **Year-Abroad Scholarship**



Intercultural and educational growth from a scholarship by the Science without Borders program in the United Kingdom (2012-2013)

## REFEREES

## Prof Jason J. Ford

@ j2.ford@qut.edu.au

Queensland University of Technology Australia

## Dr Alejandro Donaire

@ alejandro.donaire@newcastle.edu.au

➤ The University of Newcastle Australia

## **Prof Aurélio Tergolina Salton**

@ aurelio.salton@ufrgs.br

✓ UFRGS

Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

## Prof Dario F. G. Azevedo

@ dario@pucrs.br

PUCRS

Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

## **Dr. Edward Stewart**

@ e.j.c.stewart@bham.ac.uk

University of Birmingham United Kingdom

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Lecturer (Professor Assistente)

#### **PUCRS**

## Feb 2018 - Dec 2018

## Modules Taught:

- Industrial Automation
- Robot Programming
- Discrete-Event System Simulation

#### Porto Alegre, Brazil

- Integrated Manufacturing Systems
- Control Systems Analysis (Laboratory)
- Modelling for 3D Printing

## Research Assistant

## **LABIMA (Image Lab) - PUCRS**

## Aug 2015 - Jan 2017

Porto Alegre, Brazil

Research focused in automatic shadow removal from aerial images for the United States Air Force Grant regarding the shadow problem. In Jan 2016, visited The University of New Mexico and Transparent Sky.

#### Accomplishments

- Development of near-real time automatic shadow detection software powered by GPU processing, using OpenCV and CUDA technologies.
- Teaching Assistantship in undergraduate Signals and Systems course.

## **Internship Placement**

## **Birmingham Centre for Railway Research and Education**

# Jun 2013 - Sep 2013

**♀** Birmingham, UK

Activities involved the development of projects and maintenance of machinery and equipment. Focus on requirement extraction, concept design, component selection, interfacing with 3rd party hardware, firmware development, embedded programming, real-time motor control, and mechanical design and construction.

#### **Accomplishments**

• Development of self-contained autonomous measurement system embedded on a Raspberry Pi.

## RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

## **Detailed Research Experience**

### **Research Assistantship**

Worked as a Research Assistant within a United States Air Force Grant looking at an image processing methodology to remove shadows of aerial images. From Aug 2015 to Jan 2018.

### **Scholarship and Grants**

Had a scholarship from Cordenação de Aperfeiçoamento de Pessoal de Ensino Superior (CAPES) covering tuition fees during his Masters of Science. **From Aug 2015 to Aug 2017.** 

## **PUBLICATIONS**

## Journal Articles

Guilherme F. Silva et al. "Near real-time shadow detection and removal in aerial motion imagery application". In: ISPRS Journal of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing 140 (2018). Geospatial Computer Vision, pp. 104–121. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2017.11.005.